<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>White Paper on Thinking as Algorithm</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/categories/white-paper/</link>
    <description>Recent content in White Paper on Thinking as Algorithm</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/categories/white-paper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Invent More, Toil Less</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/library/beyer_etal_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/library/beyer_etal_2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Beyer, Gleason, O&amp;rsquo;Connor, Rau (2016), &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usenix.org/system/files/login/articles/login_fall16_08_beyer.pdf&#34;&gt;Invent More, Toil Less&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;;login:(41:3)&lt;/em&gt; at USENIX.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;flash flash-full flash my-2&#34;&gt;&#xA;    the Google SRE team identifies &lt;strong&gt;toils&lt;/strong&gt; in running production services and talks about their experiences in how to reduce these toils. A case example the from BigTable SRE team illustrated an incremental process that involved both management and tech teams to reduce toils effectively.&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-concept-toil&#34;&gt;Key Concept: &lt;strong&gt;toil&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Toil&lt;/em&gt; is the kind of work tied to running a production service that tends to be: &lt;strong&gt;Manual, Repetitive, Automatable and not requiring human judgment, Interrupt-driven and reactive, and Of no enduring value&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potential downside of high initial visual acuity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/library/vogeslang_etal_sinha_2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/library/vogeslang_etal_sinha_2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vogelsang, L., Gilad-Gutnick, S., Ehrenberg, E., Yonas, A., Diamond, S., Held, R., &amp;amp; Sinha, P. (2018). Potential downside of high initial visual acuity. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 115(44), 11333-11338.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vogelsang and colleagues tried to test one interesting hypothesis: seeing sharp, clear images at the very early stage of life can actually do harm to visual perception and its development. The hypothesis started with an observation that infants who have cataracts but cured at early age may actually have problems in face recognition. The authors approached this hypothesis by first using image-analysis techniques to show blurry images may require the development of large receptive fields of neurons in visual cortices. Then, they tried to train Deep Neural Networks with images blurred (or filtered) by different Gaussian filters. They found that training that started with blurry images can help the network to achieve better performance in the end.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
