<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Job Searching on Thinking as Algorithm</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/job-searching/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Job Searching on Thinking as Algorithm</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/job-searching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Offer Negotiation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/offer_negotiation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/offer_negotiation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference&#34;&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Read these first, then read them again.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://haseebq.com/my-ten-rules-for-negotiating-a-job-offer/&#34;&gt;Ten Rules for Negotiating a Job Offer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://haseebq.com/how-not-to-bomb-your-offer-negotiation/&#34;&gt;How Not to Bomb Your Offer Negotiation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kalzumeus.com/2012/01/23/salary-negotiation/&#34;&gt;Salary Negotiation: Make More Money, Be More Valued&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-average-cost-of-recruiting-an-engineer-in-Silicon-Valley/answer/Rick-Brownlow?srid=tvlO&#34;&gt;What is the average cost of recruiting an engineer in Silicon Valley?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;reading-notes&#34;&gt;Reading Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Get everything in writing&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;people, team, work responsibility&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Always keep the door open&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t say “yes, that sounds amazing, when do I start?”  &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; you implicitly accept the offer and completely close the door on the negotiation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t say “can you do 90K instead of 85K?” &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; This also closes the door. They will just accept it and bargaining against &amp;ndash; anchoring effect.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Information is power&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Do not disclose your card too fast&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yeah, [COMPANY_NAME] sounds great! I really thought this was a good fit, and I’m glad that you guys agree. Right now I’m talking with a few other companies so I can’t speak to the specific details of the offer until I’m done with the process and get closer to making a decision. But I’m sure we’ll be able to find a package that we’re both happy with, because I really would love to be a part of the team&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Always be positive&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Don’t be the decision maker&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;discuss it with my [FAMILY/CLOSE_FRIENDS/SIGNIFICANT_OTHER].&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;just wanted to confirm I had all the details right.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Have alternatives&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When you receive an offer, often the first thing you should ask for is more time to make your decision. Especially in your first offer, more time is by far the most valuable thing you can ask for.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It cost $12,000 to $24,000 to hire an Engineer&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, okay. I know that the average software engineer in Silicon Valley makes roughly 120K a year salary. So I think that’s a good place to start.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Proclaim reasons for everything&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Give specific reasons for negotiation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The more unobjectionable and sympathetic your reason, the better. If it’s medical expenses, or paying off student loans, or taking care of family, you’ll bring tears to their eyes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Be motivated by more than just money&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Whatever you assert should be something you’ve touched on earlier in your discussions, but it’s okay to repeat it now as a gentle reminder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Understand what they value&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Actually be motivated by other things.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;understand what the company values.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sign up bonus&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Equity&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Be winnable&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use Phone over email&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;your previous e-mail, I’d prefer to discuss the details of the offer over e-mail. I sometimes get nervous during important phone calls, so discussing the offer over e-mail helps me to keep a clear head and communicate more clearly. I hope this is okay with you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Change your mindset&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Virtually any amount of money available to you personally is mouse droppings to your prospective employer.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Only negotiate salary after you have agreement in principle from someone with hiring authority that, if a mutually acceptable compensation can be agreed upon, you will be hired. This is really, really important because it has direct implications for your negotiating strategy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This means that &lt;strong&gt;any discussion of compensation prior to hearing Yes-If is premature&lt;/strong&gt;.  If you’re still at the job interview and you’re talking price you are doing something wrong.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You will have much, much better results if your job search looks something more like:&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(Optional but recommended) Establish a reputation in your field as someone who delivers measurable results vis-a-vis improving revenue or reducing costs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Have a hiring manager talk with you, specifically, about an opening that they want you, specifically, to fill.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Talk informally (and then possibly formally) and come to the conclusion that this would be a great thing if both sides could come to a mutually fulfilling offer.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Let them take a stab at what that mutually fulfilling offer would look like.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Suggest ways that they could improve it such that the path is cleared for you doing that voodoo that you do so well to improve their revenue and/or reduce their costs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(Optional) Give the guy hiring you a resume to send to HR, for their records.  Nobody will read it, because resumes are an institution created to mean that no one has to read resumes.  Since no one will read it, we put it in the process where it literally doesn’t matter whether it happens or not, because if you had your job offer contingent on a document that everyone knows no one reads, that would be pretty effing stupid now wouldn’t it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Rules from Kalzumeus:&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Never Give A Number First&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Listen To What People Tell You.  Repeat It Back To Them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Research, Research, Research&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;New Information Is Valuable And Can Be Traded For Things You Want&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You Have A Multi-Dimensional Preference Set.  Use It.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;For Your Further Perusal&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Job Search Reflection</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/job_search_reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/job_search_reflection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;general-requirements&#34;&gt;General requirements&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After several successful and unsuccessful research and internship experiences, I think I wanna a position that has the following general features:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Intellectual Challenging Problems&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Collaborative and Supportive Colleagues&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Healthy, enriched personal growth and career developments&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Real impacts on users, products, systems and companies&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;problem-solving&#34;&gt;Problem Solving&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The problems are interesting, exciting, and challenging, so that I am excited to solve them and can feel sense of achievement for providing a solution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
