<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SYSADMIN on 思算</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/sysadmin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SYSADMIN on 思算</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/sysadmin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Postmortem Action Items</title>
      <link>http://example.org/library/research_article/lunney_leuder_beyer_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/library/research_article/lunney_leuder_beyer_2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interrupt Reduction Projects</title>
      <link>http://example.org/library/research_article/beyer_tobin_fong-jones_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/library/research_article/beyer_tobin_fong-jones_2016/</guid>
      <description>Teams that write and maintain software much decide how to allocate people&amp;rsquo;s time between:
 On-call/pager response: Immediate response to outages  critical to the immediate health of the service, and requires a response with an urgency of minutes. time-sensitive mitigation with in-depth investigation changes to prevent recurrence   Tickets and interrupts: Medium-urgency production issues and customer issues  have an urgency of days to weeks and usually take between minutes and hours to resolve use BUG or ticket-tracking tools   Project work: Proactive development and systems/network engineering work  have an urgency ranging from weeks to the long backlog of wishlist ideas every team maintains This type of work requires multiple days of sustained concentration in order to facilitate cognitive flow state    toil: pager response &amp;amp; tickets/interrupts</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invent More, Toil Less</title>
      <link>http://example.org/library/research_article/beyer_etal_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/library/research_article/beyer_etal_2016/</guid>
      <description>Key Concept: toil Toil is the kind of work tied to running a production service that tends to be: Manual, Repetitive, Automatable and not requiring human judgment, Interrupt-driven and reactive, and Of no enduring value.
As reported by SREs at Google, our top three sources of toil (in descending order) are:
 Interrupts (non-urgent service-related messages and emails) On-call (urgent) responses Releases and pushes  Roles  Software engineering Involves writing or modifying code, in addition to any associated design and documentation work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
